(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Yeah, let's go!
What the biboo?!
Dang it!
Oh Bijou...
Oh, what's going on?
Where... Where am I?
No way! Did I get sucked into the game world?
Whoa... What do I do?
Hello? Hello?
Oh, why are there so many eyes on me?
They're not saying anything.
Oh, I have to get back!
Today is such an important day! I can't get stuck in here!
Ugh, what should I do?
I guess I have to figure this out on my own.
There's so many people looking at me...
...are those Pebbles? Hello?
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should sing and dance? Because this looks like a stage.
Maybe...
Wait, how'd I get out? Okay.
Okay, I got it then.
I'm gonna sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This game!
This game
Lyrics: 勇気真由美 Music: 若林充
Lyrics: Mayumi Yuuki Music: Mitsuru Wakabayashi
回り続ける
Revolving endlessly
歯車にはなり下がらない
I won't settle for being just another gear
平均演じる
Playing the part of average
誕生から始まった地獄
Hell that began from birth
遊び半分で 神々導いた
Half in jest, led by the gods
盤上の世界 No No No Game No Life
To a world on a game board, No No No Game No Life
ぬるい平穏を ばっさり切り捨てて
Casting aside lukewarm peace
栄光の階段に存在刻むんだ
I'll carve my existence into the stairs of glory
目に映るのは 完全勝利の運命
What I see is the destiny of total victory
何もかも 計算どおり
Everything is exactly as calculated
変えてやる 染まらない空白で
I'll change it with an unstainable Blank
We are maverick 救済なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need salvation
どんな不条理も 勝てばいいだけの話
No matter the absurdity, it's just a matter of winning
最後の駆け引きと 才能が無敗誘う
The final stratagem and talent invite invincibility
生まれ堕ちた日に誓った 楽しむさ
I swore on the day I was born to enjoy it
自分だけの道を 自分信じてる
I believe in myself on my own path
心底に潜む
Lurking in the depths of my heart
闇より強い愛ではない
Is not a love stronger than darkness
挫ける限り
As long as I don't falter
そこに敗北はありえない
Defeat is impossible there
上辺の個体で 安心と引き換えに
In exchange for security with a superficial existence
プライド殺すな No No No Sense of Life
Don't kill your pride, No No No Sense of Life
野蛮な雑音を きっぱり拒絶して
Flatly rejecting the barbaric noise
誰より純粋な声上げるんだ
I'll raise a voice purer than anyone's
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが 教えてくれた
The feedback told me so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if I lose everything, I'll survive and win
We are maverick 常識なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need common sense
前ならえ向かう 先に待ってるのは退屈
What awaits ahead of following the crowd is boredom
誰かの言いなりじゃ つまらない 挑んでやる
It's boring to just do as told, I'll challenge it
生まれ堕ちた日を誇りにして
Taking pride in the day I was born
自分だけの道を 最後まで
My own path until the end
迷わない 選ばれし者の
Without hesitation, even if it's the
真っ赤な自惚れでも
Deep-red conceit of the chosen one
誇らしく 生き抜くための
Because I only know one way
方法をひとつしか知らないから
To live through it proudly
We are maverick 救済なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need salvation
どんな不条理も 勝てばいいだけの話
No matter the absurdity, it's just a matter of winning
最後の駆け引きと 才能が無敗誘う
The final stratagem and talent invite invincibility
生まれ堕ちた日に誓った 楽しむさ
I swore on the day I was born to enjoy it
この世界手にして 笑うんだ
I'll take this world in my hands and laugh
We are maverick 最強の名ばかりゲーマー
We are maverick, the strongest gamers in name only
空白ならば 何物にも 何物にもなれる
If we are Blank, we can become anything, anything
自分だけの道を 自分信じてる
I believe in myself on my own path
Yeah! How was that?
That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey over there!
You liked it, right? Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
Alright, ready? Beam me up, pebbles!
Ah! Ah!
Why is it...?
No!
Guys, where are you going?
Dang it.
Well, according to video game logic,
this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that!
I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh? Huh? Oh, what's this?
I mean, I came out through there, so
maybe this will take me... you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here. So...
Let's go!
Huh? Huh? I'm not back in my world? Eh?
ここどこ？
Where am I?
待ってたよ、ビブー。
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Robocosan Joins the Battle!
Eh? Eh? Roboco-senpai!
探しているのは、これ？
Is this what you're looking for?
Ah! Coin! The coin!
MISSION: Reclaim the scattered coins from each stage's Game Master!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんでしょ？
Without this, you can't get back to your world, right?
でも、そうはさせない。
But I won't let that happen.
ゲームマスターである僕たちから、
From us Game Masters...
すべて取り戻せるかな？
...can you take them all back?
Wait, really? Can I not go back... wait...
とにかく！このコインが欲しければ、僕と勝負だ！
Anyway! If you want this coin, challenge me!
A match?
そう！ Yes！ 格闘ゲームで勝負だ！
So! Yes! Let's settle this with a fighting game!
All right! I won't lose!
Wait, what? No!
リモコン
Remote Control
L & R & UP & DOWN & B & B & A & B & S(tart)
L & R & Dash & & B & B & A & B & S(tart)
L & R & Dash & & B & B & A & B & STOP
L & R & Dash & & B & B & A & B & TALK
L & R & Dash & & B & B & A & B & S(tart)
これが私をリモートでコントロールする機械です
This is the machine that controls me remotely.
少し歪な形しておりますが使えます
It's a bit of an odd shape, but it works.
UP SIDE DOWN LEFT RIGHT
L R & Dash & B B A B S
もうちょっとで外に出られるのにな
I was so close to being able to go outside...
どうしてもうまくいかね まだ まだ 足りない
No matter what, it doesn't go well. It's still not enough.
SIT DOWN! PLEASE!
FEEDBACKに身を固めて
Hardened by feedback...
巡る 巡る TURN IT ROUND
Round and round, turn it round.
唸り上げてモーター状態
Roaring like a motor...
踊る 踊る DANCING NIGHT
Dancing, dancing night.
MASH UP！ 溢れ出なく 分かる
Mash up! Overflowing, I understand.
声を上げて SINGING NOW
Raise your voice, singing now.
あの子よりも上手く歌いたい
I want to sing better than that girl.
これが僕をリモートで操縦できる機械です
This is the machine that can control me remotely.
説明書は紛失しておりますが使えます
The instruction manual is missing, but it works.
空から降ってみたいつもの顔
That usual face that seemed to fall from the sky
余裕でしょう
It's easy, right?
今日はかなり本気だぜ
I'm quite serious today
ほらすぐ決めて
Look, decide right away
座る座る sit down please
Sit, sit, sit down please
トークバックを頭に差して
Plug the talkback into your head
回る回る turn around
Turn, turn, turn around
ちょっと待ってスタンバイ状態
Wait a moment, standby state
踊る踊る dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
ジャストフィットなリズムを出して
Bring out the perfect-fit rhythm
唸り上げる singing now
Roaring, singing now
あいつよりも高く歌いたい
I want to sing higher than them
惚れた腫れたの七色ざむらい
Infatuated and swollen, seven-colored samurai
洗いざらい主張する存在
An existence that asserts everything
思い違いが透けてる按配
A state where misunderstandings are transparent
怖いくらいの惑星か状態
A state of planet-ization that's almost scary
気にしないのがあなたのポリシー
Not caring is your policy
悩んでいてもお腹はヘルシー
Even if you're worried, your stomach is healthy
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
One way or another, the world is healthy
お気を確かにぬるま湯男子
Get a grip, lukewarm water boy
もうちょっとでスキマ埋まるのに
Although the gap is almost filled
なのになのに
And yet, and yet
どうやっても上手くいかねぇ
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well
あー、もう時間が足りない
Ah, I'm out of time already
座る座る sit down please
Sit, sit, sit down please
フィードバックに身体溶けてくる
My body is melting into the feedback
巡る巡る turn around
Go 'round, go 'round, turn around
唸り上げてもだ状態
Roaring even in this state
踊る踊る dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
マッシュアップでもれなくアガる
I'll definitely get hyped with a mash-up
声を上げて singing now
Raise your voice, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl
座る座る sit down please
Sit, sit, sit down please
巡る巡る turn around
Go 'round, go 'round, turn around
踊る踊る dancing night
Dance, dance, dancing night
声を上げて singing now
Raise your voice, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl
Wahoo! I win!
No... Bijou...
Are you okay?
Ah! A coin! Yay! I got a coin!
Go to the next stage...
But be careful...
次のゲームマスターは僕のようには行かないぞ
The next game master won't be as easy as me.
No easy mode.
It's okay! Because I'm Biboo!
Okay.
Thanks, Senpai! Bye bye!
Bye bye!
Whoa!
There... whew!
Now then... where to next, I wonder?
We've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Wow!
IRyS Ninomae Ina'nis Joins the Battle! Driving Battle
Huh? IRyS? Ina?
I'm assuming this is what you're looking for, right?
Why are you guys so cool? Yes! Yes! I need that! I need that! Yes!
Give me! Give me! I need that coin! Give me! Give me!
We won't just hand it over.
You'll have to race us for it.
Ah?
Yes.
No way! Give me! Give me! Where are you putting that?
I'm putting that back in my pocket.
No! Where is it going? Oh my god!
If you want it, you have to beat us. Are you ready to battle?
Fine! I'll be cool too, watch this!
Oh hey! I won't lose-a!
Heh!
No one can stop our shine tonight
No one can stop our shine
Hi!
Save me, I think I'm freezing out, so cold inside
What type of princess rules and looks at you?
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
What is it that you're matching up?
Inside the maze of your heart, I'm the soul that strayed
That's right baby look at me, you're not fine
Oh can't you see that I can be refined?
Your heart
Is super hard right now
It's time to be your diamond girlfriend!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul
Break it all break it all break it all, the diamond girlfriend!
逆転! Get up, Get up, Get up, yo-hi! Beat on my toy
Reversal! Get up, Get up, Get up, yo-hi! Beat on my toy
撒き散らすのは Bling Bling の Sparkle
Scattering around a Bling Bling Sparkle
Just hit it and wheel it, Make this all buttery
眩しい Stardom 目がくらんじゃう
Dazzling Stardom, it'll make you blind
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
希望のない世界で触れて
Touch me in a world without hope
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
勇気が溶けちゃうほどに
Until your courage melts away
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn
Your rebirth
I'm gonna show you who I really am
Oh yeah!
In the name of love I'll be a gem
Your heart
Is super hard right now
It's time to be your diamond girlfriend!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul
Break it all break it all break it all
No one can stop my heart tonight
Now see us, your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回る真っ赤っかになるまで Wimbo
Spinning round and round until it turns bright red, Wimbo
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
The more you lack love, the deeper the darkness
Tashigizan Gem 扱う I'm a jeweler
Dealing in Addition Gem, I'm a jeweler
さあ踊りなさい!
Now, dance!
Shine on, shine bright like my flame
Until it all melts away
Are you ready?!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me let them light the way
Diamond girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul
Break it all break it all break it all
No one can stop my heart tonight
YATTA! Woohoo! Are you guys okay?
Uwaaa! (Distressed sounds from IRyS and Ina)
That hit you hard!
YES! I GOT THE COIN!
I'm the winner! I win! Yay!
Huh? Oh!
A portal! A portal!
By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
Uh... It... Don't worry about it!
It came from my Nephilim pocket!
Uwaaaa! Oh no! Goodbye!
Uwaaaa! The world is spinning! Aaaah!
Whoa!
Ugh... Oh... I'm dizzy... Ugh...
Huh? Is this the Puzzle Stage?
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge!
Now, hey, come out! Hey!
Huh?
There's no game master this time?
Eh?
Well, I guess I could use a break or something then.
Hmm... maybe I'll dance and sing by myself,
you know, as a refresher.
Yes! I'll be ready for the next challenge.
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me
of a certain song.
Hey! Everyone over there!
You want to hear it too, right?
Yeah!
Okay, they didn't say anything,
I'm just talking to myself.
Wow! All right then, let's dance...
Tetris!
どして どして どして どして どして どしてしまうの
Why, why, why, why, why do I end up doing it?
どしんて くるしんでしまうわと
Thumping down, I'll end up suffering
どしんて ふりきって いきましょうか
Thumping down, shall we shake it off and go?
悪くない
Not bad
今日も 続々 派手 感動
Today too, one after another, flashy emotions
錠を 薬 食べればと
If I take the pills like medicine
どーひーて フル 認め 暗号か
Thumping down, fully acknowledging, is it a code?
兼ねによる
It depends on the money
常識 デクル イフル ラント
Common sense, decry, influence, rant
放って 削って いければ 満点
If I can let go and scrape by, it's a perfect score
正信 デクル システム キャンセル
True belief, decry, system cancel
どして どして どして どして どして どしてしまうの
Why, why, why, why, why do I end up doing it?
どして どして 行ってしまうの
Why, why do you end up going?
どして どー 壊れちゃったかな
Why, did it break down?
近未来 的 カカタン
Near-futuristic clatter
ショッピングモール 現代 コンフィ
Shopping mall, modern config
消費どし かかったん
Consumption clatter
保持ホール な 経費で ピンボール
Maintenance hole, pinball at cost
割れも さし 100 どしゃ 足を つき
Cracks appearing, 100 thumps, touching the ground
優先 オートウェイ ッテッテッテ... ッテッテッテ トリス
Priority autoway, Te-te-te... te-te-te Tetris
どして こんな 目に
Why this fate?
興味がないことほど 本気じゃないもの
The things I'm not interested in,
the things I'm not serious about
全部後回しで
Putting them all off
知ってることは 知らぬふり
Pretending not to know the things I do
私は終わっている
I am finished
恥ずかしい 隠してる奴らの 記憶 消し去って
Erase the memories of those hiding their shame
迷惑かけて ごめんって言えば
If I say I'm sorry for causing trouble
ねえ 誰か 助けて
Hey, someone save me
どして すぐ 光っちゃうの
Why does it light up right away?
知りたくない 知りたくない 知りたくない
I don't want to know, I don't want to know,
I don't want to know
もぉ 皆 すぐ 光っちゃうさぁ と
Already, everyone lights up right away
どっしんて くる 痛手 まど
Thumping down comes the heavy blow
行きたくない 行きたくない 行きたくない
I don't want to go, I don't want to go,
I don't want to go
バイバイ
Bye bye
認知救急 センター ボル
Cognitive emergency center ball
ナイチンゲール な 配信 ゲーム
Nightingale-like streaming game
名刺 交換 の メーシン
Business card exchange superstition
ジャギボール で 千切る ハイボール
Jagged ball, tearing highball
温泉 旅行 と 豊岡 諸事 つき
Hot spring trip and various matters in Toyooka
早く生きて ッテッテッテ... ッテッテッテ トリス
Hurry and live, Te-te-te... te-te-te Tetris
超 完成 シュウ ヂヂ
Super completion, shuu di-di
嘘とか そとか 忙しくて 眠れない わけ 今日も
Lies and such, outside and such,
I'm so busy I can't sleep today either
誰が早く 殴って 気づかせてくれよ
Someone, punch me quickly and make me realize
人生 キャンセル キャンセル 界隈 ぼんやりとした 不安
Life cancel, cancel neighborhood, a vague anxiety
私のせい 私が悪いよ そうだよ
It's my fault, I'm the bad one, that's right
興味が出て も 本気でやって も 全部 空回り で
Even if I get interested, even if I get serious,
everything is in vain
いらない癖に 嘘つき
Even though I don't need it, I'm a liar
私は終わっている
I am finished
恥ずかしい 隠してる奴らの 記憶 消し去って
Erase the memories of those hiding their shame
迷惑かけて ごめんって言えば
If I say I'm sorry for causing trouble
ねえ 誰か 助けて
Hey, someone save me
迷惑かけて ごめんって言えば
If I say I'm sorry for causing trouble
ねえ 誰か 許して
Hey, someone forgive me
Whoa... ah...
Oh, I'm dizzy.
That scared me!
I don't know, this game's bugged, man.
Hey, someone report these bugs, dang it!
Cubes start popping out and everything's hard.
Who designed this? I need to meet the devs.
Hey devs!
This game is malfunction,
but I don't have time for that.
I gotta find the coins!
Eh?
Oh! I guess that's my cue to leave.
Okay! Next stage, let's charge up!
Helicopter! Helicopter!
Ugh... so...
I gotta work on that landing.
Oh! Wow! What a cute stage!
かわいい！
Kawaii!
Ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho!
Oh?
どうもどうも、待ってましたよ、ビブー。
Hello hello, I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle!
Crane Game Battle
フブキ先輩！
Fubuki-senpai!
ビブー、これがほしいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, right?
ほしい！ほしい！
I want it! I want it!
ならば白上と勝負だ！
Then it's a match with Shirakami!
白上のクレーンゲームから果たして逃げられるかな？
I wonder if you can escape from
Shirakami's crane game?
Eh... hmm...
Okay then! 負けないよ！
Okay then! I won't lose!
勝負！
Match!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
ひだまり
A sunny spot
さんさん
Shining brightly
心は
My heart is
晴れ模様
Like a clear sky
二つの
My two
瞳は
Eyes
ひまわり
Are like
の種のよう
Sunflower seeds
語らい
Talking
重なり
Overlapping
塊
Clumping
絡まり
Entwining
一緒にいること
Being together
絶対 必然
Is absolutely inevitable
でもあなた大事な 夢を描く
But you're painting an important dream
終わるまではずっと ここで待ってるよ
Until it's over, I'll be waiting right here
Lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Please don't stop
Lonely rolling star
さあ前を向いて 行こう
Come on, look forward and let's go
星空
Starry sky
キラキラ
Sparkling
金平糖のようだよ
It's just like star candy
甘くて切ない
Sweet and painful
思いが募るの
Feelings are building up
抱きしめた想いは
The feelings I embraced
夜空を舞い
Dance through the night sky
急降下して
Swooping down
あなたの元へ 届くかな
I wonder if they'll reach you
Lonely rolling star
諦めないでよね
Don't give up, okay?
Lonely rolling star
たまには電話して
Call me once in a while
Lonely rolling star
会いたいよ 今すぐ
I want to see you right now
Lonely rolling star
溜息が一つ
A single sigh
こぼれる
Spills out
再会待つあの場所で
At that place where we wait to reunite
待ち合わせしようか
Shall we meet up?
Lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Please don't stop
Lonely rolling star
思い出してよね
Please remember
Lonely rolling star
待っているから
Because I'm waiting
なーなーなななーなーなーなななーなななーなななー...
Na na na na na na na na na na...
なーなーなななーなーなーなななーなーなななーなななー...
さぁ　前を向いて行こう
Now, let's face forward and go
なーなーなななーなーなーなななーなーなななーなななー...
Na na na na na na na na na na...
Yeah! I won! I won!
あれ、負けちゃった... あれ、BP使っちゃった...
No way, I lost... No, I used up all my BP...
あひゃひゃ、ボコボコにされちゃったよ
Ahaha, I got beaten up!
コインだ！イエーイ！
A coin! Yay!
コインゲットだね！イエーイ！
You got a coin! Yay!
I'm the winner!
可愛いから許して！
Forgive me because I'm cute!
しょうがない、許す！可愛いからねぇ！
I have no choice but to forgive you! Since you're cute!
じゃあ次の世界へ、ビブー！
Well, on to the next world, Biboo!
あ！手伝って！
Ah! Help me!
あー、先輩お願い！
Ah, Senpai, please!
はーい、行くぞ！レッツゴー、こせきー！
Alright, here I go! Let's go, Koseki!
Ah, there! I think we're doing great now, aren't we?
Who's next?
I'm ready for my next challenge!
待っていたぞ、ビブー！
I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Hajime!
WHAT?!
これが欲しければ、わらわと勝負だ！
If you want this, challenge me!
My coin! Whoa!
始めのダンスについて来られるかな？
I wonder if you can keep up with my dance?
Eh? Dance?
Hmm...
Okay! Let's dance...
...together!
Yeah! Yeah!
みんなー！チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー！
Everyone! Cirno's math class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！
Aim to be a genius like me and do your best!
がんばっていってね！
Do your best!
キラキラダイアモンド
Kira kira diamond
輝く星のように
Like a shining star
栄光　志望校　なんとかして入ろう
Glory, dream school, let's get in somehow
天才　秀才　トップ目指して　GO GO!!
Genius, talent, aim for the top, GO GO!!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
あたい、バカじゃないもん！
I'm not a baka!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
「バカ」っていうほうがバカなのよ！
Calling someone a baka makes you a baka!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
なによ、うるさいわね、このバカ！
What? You're annoying, you baka!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
紅魔館からバスが出て
A bus left from the Scarlet Devil Mansion
初めに三人乗りました
First, three people got on
白玉楼で一人降りて
One got off at Hakugyokurou
半人だけ乗りました
Only half a person got on
八雲さんちで二人降りて
Two got off at Yakumo's place
結局乗客合計何人だ？
In the end, how many passengers were there?
答えは答えはゼロ人ゼロ人
The answer is, the answer is zero, zero
なぜならなぜならそれは
Because, because that's
幻想郷にバス無い
There are no buses in Gensokyo
山落ち意味などないわ
There's no point in a climax or a resolution
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
As long as the characters are well-established
元気があればなんでも
If you've got energy, you can do anything
①　②　⑨！
1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針
Round and round go the hands of the clock
ぐるぐる頭まわる
Round and round my head spins
だってつぶら目玉
Even though I only have
二つしかないのに
Two little eyes
三本の針なんてちんぷんかん
Three clock hands are just gibberish
次々問題出る
Problems appear one after another
まだまだ授業続く
The lesson still continues
凍る部屋の中ひんやりした温度も
In the frozen room, the chilly temperature
時間も気にせずゆっくりしていってね
And the time don't matter, so take it easy
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
だから、バカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！
I said I'm not a baka!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
いい加減にしないと冷凍するわよ！
Stop it, or I'll freeze you!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！
And then you'll just have to die in a bunch of pieces!
バーカバーカバーカバーカ
Baka baka baka baka
霊夢んとこの百万えんの
Someone broke that 1,000,000 yen pot
壺を誰かが割っちゃった
At Reimu's place
永遠亭のえーりんが
Eirin from Eientei
弁償しに来ましたよ
Came to pay for it
知らんぷりのイタズラでね
It was just a prank, I feigned ignorance
結局賠償金額いくら？
In the end, how much was the compensation?
答えは答えはゼロ円ゼロ円
The answer is, the answer is zero yen, zero yen
なぜならなぜならそれは
Because, because that's
そんな壺あるわけない
There's no way such a pot exists
常識超えたところに
Beyond common sense
世界の真理がある
Lies the truth of the world
秘密の数字目指して
Aiming for the secret number
①　②　⑨！
1, 2, 9!
ヘラヘラニヤけながら
Grinning foolishly
ゲラゲラ笑いながら
Laughing out loud
うっざー！
So annoying!
因幡ウサギ 可愛げもないのに 新参の ゾウどもは ホイホイホイ
Inaba bunny, not even cute, but the new elephants go 'hoi hoi hoi'
再生百万回 もれなく 愚民なんて どういうことなのよ
A million views, and everyone's a fool? What's that about?
どちらかって言うなら サーバー管理も お疲れさんってとこにゃ
If anything, I should say "thanks for the hard work" to the server management.
わかった！ アタイがあまりにも天才だから嫉妬してるんでしょ！
I get it! You're just jealous because I'm such a genius!
ほんと、しょうがないわね！ せっかくだからアタイの天才の秘訣をちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ！
Honestly, you're hopeless! Since you're here, I'll let you in on just a bit of my genius secret!
あたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいの あたいのあたいの H2O
My, my, my, my, my, my, my, my, H2O
集めて集めて集めて集めて束ねても
Collect, collect, collect, collect, and bundle them up
あたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいの あたいのあたいの丈夫な頭に
My, my, my, my, my, my, my, my, inside my sturdy head
集まれ集まれ集まれ集まれ変わらない
Gather, gather, gather, gather, it never changes
あためてあためてあためてあためてあためてあためて あためて食べたら
Warm them, warm them, warm them, warm them, warm them, warm them, and if I eat them warm
あの子のあの子のあの子のあの子の手をひねる
I'll twist that kid's, that kid's, that kid's, that kid's arm
あたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいの 完璧 いわゆるいわゆるいわゆるいわゆる パーフェクト！
My, my, my, my, my, my, perfection, in other words, in other words, in other words, in other words, perfect!
ひゃくおくちょうまんバッチリよ！
One hundred billion trillion, perfectly!
山落ち意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
Climax, resolution, it's all meaningless, as long as the character stands out!
元気があればなんでも 1、2、9！
With energy, you can do anything: 1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針 くるくる頭まわる
Round and round go the clock hands, round and round my head spins,
だって つぶら目玉 2つしかないのに 三本の針なんて ちんぷんかんぷん
Because I've only got two round eyeballs, but three hands on a clock? It's all Greek to me.
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problems come out one after another, the lesson keeps going on and on.
凍る部屋の中 ひやりとした温度も 時間も気にせずゆっくりしていってね
Inside the frozen room, don't mind the chilly temperature or the time, just take it easy!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
もうバカでいいわよ、知らないっ！
Fine, I'm an idiot then, I don't care!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
ふーっ、速めのダンスについてこれるなんて、なかなかやるな！
Phew! Being able to keep up with that fast dance, you're pretty good!
やったー！
I did it!
よし、コインをやるぞ。ほい！
Alright, here's a coin. Take it!
やったー！ イエーイ！
Yay! Woo-hoo!
I got a coin!
はっ、はじめー！ Thank you for dancing with me!
Ha-Hajime! Thank you for dancing with me!
めっちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
楽しかった、ありがとう！ Thank you!
It was fun, thank you! Thank you!
じゃあ、 I must go.
Well then, I must go.
うおー、オッケー！ バイバイー！
Whoa, okay! Bye-bye!
Bye bye! Let's go!
ふー... Oh.
Phew... Oh.
Oh, we're already okay... Ah, I see.
Whoa! What's next then?
The rest is... let me count...
One, two...
Two challenges left, I think, for two coins!
ほっ、はっ、はっ、はっ！
Ho, ha, ha, ha!
待っといたぞ、ビブー！
I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
ビブー！
Biboo!
Amane Kanata La+ Darknesss Joins the Battle!
えっ、かなた先輩？ ラプラス？
Eh, Kanata-senpai? La+?
What are you doing here?
これが欲しければ、我々と勝負だ！
If you want this, you'll have to face us!
うわっ、My coin!
Whoa, my coin!
勝負だ！
It's a showdown!
迫りくるゾンビを全部倒すことが、できるかな！？
Can you defeat all the approaching zombies!?
おー、うわー。じゃ、お手柔らかにー...
Oh, whoa. Well, go easy on me...
しない！
Not!
Make It Out Alive Lyrics, Music: Taka, Kane Churko, Jamil Kazmi
Far away, far away, far away you...
Tryna put the pressure on
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere to go
No road is left to run
Our souls, our souls weigh tons
Demons close to shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on
'Cause we haven't had enough
Don't give up the fight
Make it out alive
Set this heart on fire, woah, woah, woah
Don't give up it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you down, woah, woah, woah
We're gonna make it out alive!
Tonight, tonight, tonight,
I'm screaming on the inside.
I'll live it for this life.
Gotta faith, gotta faith beyond the unknown,
It's the only way to live.
Gotta go, gotta go, gotta go,
Somewhere that I've never been.
Watch the fire...
...rise!
Make it out alive!
Set this world on fire now!
Whoa, whoa!
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright!
'Cause I won't let you burn now!
Whoa, whoa!
We're gonna make it out alive!
Make it out alive!
Set this world on fire now!
Whoa, whoa!
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright!
'Cause I won't let you burn now!
Whoa, whoa!
We're gonna make it out alive!
Yeah, make it out alive!
Yeah, make it out, make it out!
We're gonna make it out alive!
全部倒すなんて、すげーじゃん！
Defeating them all, that's amazing!
あ、終わった？
Ah, is it over?
っしゃー！よし！
Alright! Okay!
これやろう！
Let's do this!
おー！これやったー！
Oh! We did it!
じゃ、みんな、ありがとね！
Then, everyone, thank you!
おい、ハッピーバースデー！
Hey, happy birthday!
あ！
Ah!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
What do you mean?
Okay!
じゃ、さよならー！
Well then, goodbye!
くそ、立てない...
Damn, I can't stand up...
Ugh... nice landing, yeah.
Huh?
Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a progress check sort of thing?
Let's see, let's see where I'm at.
Huh? Oh!
I'm missing one more coin! But...
...where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can
like take a break and recover.
That's a good idea. You know,
I'm feeling kind of tired,
and all these songs have been so beep-beep intense.
Let's- let's take a break. I'll just a nap.
I'll- I'll wake up. Just... hold on everyone.
Just- just give me like five minutes, okay?
Just five minutes. Oyasumi-hello!
Just five minutes. Good night-hello!
You know, oyasumi-ya, oyasumi-ya.
You know, good night, good night.
Flow
Lyrics: Kathryn Cwynar, Natsuko Ishikawa
Well come and well met, my brave little spark.
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star.
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more, share of your life
Far greater than memory,
its loss and love words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed
with each brief reflection, by setting sun
By storms wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Loving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surfacewards
With your unbeating heart wish them well
Deep, dark, far away,
I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears, quench your fears
With joy til you're near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, and
Hush love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light
echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake, on winds rise again
For this journey's end is but one step
forward to tomorrow
ううう……
Uuuh...
うわぁ！ いい夢だった。
Whoa! What a good dream.
はぁ。
Haaah.
よし、それじゃあ進捗を確認しよう。
Alright, let's check our progress then.
うーん、まだコインが1枚足りないな。
Ummm, we're still missing one coin.
どこにあるんだろう？
Where could it be?
Eh? Ah!
Ah! Again! What's happening?!
What the Beep?
I've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Fake Biboo Joins the Battle!
You... you're...
I'm you.
Me?
You mean... my last opponent is me?
Exactly.
Me. You.
Your biggest enemy.
Your biggest obstacle.
Yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Bijou.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then I won't either!
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
Weight of the World / 壊レタ世界ノ歌
Weight of the World / Song of the Broken World
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky,
it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries
are inconspicuous
Tell me God,
are you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying
for my past mistakes?
This
is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れ出る色
Overflowing colors
こぼれる命
Spilling life
風は今も遠く
The wind is still far away
剥がれる錆びと
Peeling rust and
蠢めく刃
wriggling blades
花がいつか森に
The flowers will one day become a forest
これが僕の呪い
This is my curse
約束殺す痛みが
The pain of killing a promise
君の願い
Your wish
最後の夢を捨てた
Discarded the last dream
償いだけど
It's an atonement, but
そう僕らは今
So we are now
無価値でも叫ぶ
Screaming even if it's worthless
この汚れた世界の愛
The love of this stained world
そう僕らは今
So we are now
無意味でも願う
Wishing even if it's meaningless
ただ君との時間を
Just the time with you
溺れた意識は 優しいまま
The drowned consciousness remains gentle
消えて
and disappears
Weight of the World / 壊レタ世界ノ歌
Weight of the World / Song of a Broken World
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So, here we are now
無意味でも願う
Even if it's meaningless, we wish
ただ君との未来を
Simply for a future with you
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So, here we are now
無意味でも願う
Even if it's meaningless, we wish
ただ君との時間を祈り歌を
Simply for a moment with you, a prayer song
Maybe if I keep believing
祈りが赦しを
Even if my prayers
得られずとも
cannot be forgiven
My dreams will come to life
僕は...
I am...
Impressive.
Yes!
The coin!
Oh, you're so wide. Oh.
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh?
What is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah!
Hey, thanks! But um...
There can only be one.
Ha!
Oh, oh, I'm here. Oh, oh.
Hello everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in with all of these coins we have unlocked...
My new original song! Woohoo!
And guess what? The video is gonna come out right after this!
Good job everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it to you right now!
Are you ready?
Let's go out with a bang!
ROCK IN!
Lyrics: Ludokano, Koseki Bijou
Music, Arrangement: Ludokano
Biboo's here to play
Yeah, uh-huh
Uh-uh
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot
LOG IN, GET GOOD, YOU MAD? LET'S GO
TALK BEEP, GET HIT, CLEAN SWEEP
NOW YOU KNOW WHAT'S UP
HIT 'EM WITH A ONE-TWO-THREE BIBOO BIBOO
COME AND TEST YOUR LUCK
YEAH WE COMIN' IN CLUTCH BIBOO BIBOO
SKIPPING STONE IN FLIGHT
TAKE 'EM OUT ONE-SHOT BIBOO BIBOO
COME AND HELP ME FIGHT
GET-ON-UP, LET'S GO, JUST ME AND YOU
PLAYER ONE AND PLAYER TWO
WE'LL SEE THIS THROUGH
CLOSE MY EYES, MAKE A WISH
ONE MORE SHOT, I WILL NOT MISS
ROCK IN!
LEVEL UP, WE GO ONWARDS
AIMING FOR ANOTHER WIN
A DIAMOND IN THE ROUGH, IT'S KINDA TOUGH
YOU GOTTA KEEP ON ROLLING
THE GRIND GOES ON AND ON, NO BREAKS
SEAL THE CRACKS WITH A FEW BAND-AIDS
I'LL TRY OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN
Just one more round, please?
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck,
yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight,
get enough points to just be hand two
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes make a wish
One more shot I will not miss
ROCKIN'!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape, I feel the space
It's set in stone, carve it into me
I just wanna be Biboo
Biboo!
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck,
yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo
Better hit quicksave 'cause Biboo's here to play
Now you know what's up,
hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck,
yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight,
take 'em out one shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight,
get enough points to just be hand two
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes make a wish
One more shot I will not miss
ROCKIN'!
Biboo Biboo!
Uh... Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Ready to get teleported back to my world
anytime now.
Mom? Pick me up, I'm scared.
Hey! This wasn't part of the deal!
Hey! No, wait! What are you doing?
No! No! No! Nooo!
Hey! Listen to my song at least! Okay?
My song's coming out, listen to it!
LOG IN! Go! Go!
AAAAAAAAHHHH!